Giovanny González Baltazar



About

125B 298, San Nicolás

del Sur. Mérida, Yucatán.
97285 México

giovanny.gonzalez.19@g

9991454542

gggiovanny.github.io/cv/

in giovanny-gonzalezbaltazar

gggiovanny

Frontend web development

Expert

Javascript Typescript

React Redux Sagas

React Query RxJS

CSS in JS SASS

HTML/CSS Jest

Testing Library Cypress

Backend web development

Advanced

Python FastAPI NodeJS

Prisma

PHP (Laravel & Codeigniter)

T-SQL MySQL

Stored procedures ORM

REST JWT Auth0

Windows Desktop

Intermediate

C# SQL Server (T-SQL)

Stored procedures

C/C++

Mobile development

Intermediate

Kotlin Java

Summary

Bachelor in Computer Systems Engineer from the Instituto Tecnológico de Mérida, with 3 years of professional experience. I've worked on international multidisciplinary teams developing massive web products, enterprise software and custom web-based solutions for national level franchises. Proficient in many languages and frameworks (such as React and FastAPI), and experienced in Typescript, SQL, Git, PHP and agile methodologies. I have proven to be very versatile, being able to work in both backend and frontend; and with a quick adaptation to new languages, frameworks and tools, as well as an assimilation of the culture and good practices of each team I've worked on.

Experience

Grupo Bursatil Mexicano, Casa de Bolsa

Mid Front End Engineer

I was the lead frontend engineer of a GBM back-office web platform team using an AWS CI/CD pipeline.

- Convert user requirements on new features using React/Redux/Sagas/SASS
- Write unit and integration tests using React Testing Library and Jest
- Propose and implement improvements for the components and tests codebase by using state-of-the-art development patterns
- Being an ambassador of good development practices and flows for other frontend teammates
- Implement a complex modular permission system
- Greatly increase the project test coverage
- Migrate React and testing libraries versions

Boy Scouts of America

08/2021 - 05/2022

05/2022 - 08/2022

React Developer

I was frontend React developer on the international English speaker multidisciplinary team in charge of the Event Registration System for Boy Scouts of America using agile methodologies.

- Convert stories in to new features using React/Typescript/Redux/RxJS/Styled Components
- Communicate with users when it is needed in order to solve specific issues
- Always keep in sync with the design and backend teams
- Keep the codebase maintainable be keeping it modular and self-documented
- Write integration tests using Cypress
- Document processes and 'tribal knowledge' in Confluence

The Ksquare Group

07/2021 - 05/2022

01/2020 - 07/2021

Fullstack Developer

I worked as a USA nearshore developer for The Boy Scouts of America. My main goal is to deliver a high-quality result in a timely manner, following the Ksquare culture.

Génesis Aplicaciones

Junior Web Developer

I was in charge of developing and maintaining some massive web products, the main one being the TimbraXML billing web application. Besides gaining a lot of knowledge of frontend and backend web development, I learned what is a good workflow among a professional development team, supported by version control tools, progression boards and effective communication channels.

- Migrate, develop and maintain the TimbraXML billing web application
- Deliver custom web-based solutions (PHP/Codelgniter/JQuery) for national level franchises
- Turn core processes into documented libraries with modern and readable syntax
- Make flows with Git to avoid crashes between teammate's changes

Grupo Dicas

06/2019 - 12/2019

Technical Support Assistant

Originally tasked to be an assistant in technical support and server administration, I ended up doing all the engineering process to develop an Android application.

- Gather and interpret information about the experience of using software by users with little or no computer knowledge
- Used modern software design architectures (MVVM and observer pattern)
- Reverse engineer an existing system to integrate it to another with zero documentation
- Implemented a REST API with PHP and Laravel
- Secured the requests with JSON Web Tokens

Android Jetpack

Other tech skills

Git

Amazon Web Services

Agile methodologies

VS Code ninja

Linux command line

Soft skills

Analytical skills

Detail-oriented

Critical thinking

Integrity Leadership

Research

Stress management

Business vision

Written and oral communication

Languages

Spanish (Native) English (B2)

Systems development trainee

Marbol Industria Mueblera

Temporal member of the development team and mentored by Felix Amaya Valencia, from whom I quickly gained recognition and was assigned tasks of the same weight as those given to permanent members of the team. Working there, I learned to understand the importance of knowing the problems in depth before writing even a single line of code

- Design modules of the internal custom ERP system with C# Windows Forms.
- Create the backend for my modules using T-SQL tables and stored procedures.

Education

Instituto Tecnológico de Mérida

Engineer in Computer Systems Engineer 91.69

Volunteer

Scouts de México · https://scouts.org.mx/

Jefe de Tropa (YUC1990357)

2022-01-01

Awards

HackSureste 2018

Team MeseBot

Thanks to Giovanny's leadership and technical skills, Team Mesebot was recognized with third place for creating a high-impact innovation project consisting of a system to deliver restaurant orders directly from the table to the kitchen using voice commands. He received recognition, a cash prize, a pass to Talent Land in Guadalajara and an entrepreneurship mentorship that includes product registration and a registered company at zero cost.

Publications

Costeapp

Side project

An offline-first Web application (React, RXDB, react-hook-form, Bulma) for costing estimations of cooking recipes.

Asset validation application

01/2019

01/2020

Grupo Dicas

An android application (Kotlin, Jetpack) to validate the existence of fixed assets with a QR code.

FiestasMexicanas 01/2018

School project

A Windows Forms (C#, .NET) desktop application for quoting, order management and piñata production.

03/2019 - Present

08/2016 - 12/2020

06/2018 - 08/2018